for the first time ever a piece of code
a smart contract a non-person has been
added to the us sanctions list
interacting with this code can get you a
fine of more than 300 000 dollars and it
can put you in jail for up to 30 years i
am of course talking about tornado cash
a cryptocurrency mixing service that is
used by many people as a privacy tool
aimed by north korean hackers to launder
millions of dollars of stolen coins
anonymous
nicolas
we are going to talk about the tornado
cache what is it and how does it work
the u.s sanctions list and what do they
mean for the crypto industry and we will
take a look at the ugly truth that these
sanctions exposed about the ethereum
network and the problems they might have
with the upcoming merge
bitcoin is a database and all you will
find in that database are records of
people sending money to each other
transactions bitcoin is also a public
database which means that you can see a
history of all transactions and you can
trace how the coins have moved and
changed hands all the way to when they
were first mined now that is a privacy
problem and that is the reason why
bitcoin is not the best tool to do money
laundering the wallets on the bitcoin
network don't have usernames but even if
they are anonymous it is fairly easy to
see which coins are moving and where
which allows exchanges to block hackers
from cashing out on their stolen profits
this is why if you are a hacker and you
want to launder money rather than using
bitcoin i would suggest to use a
different blockchain like ethereum
ethereum inherits the privacy problem
from bitcoin transactions are public but
where ethereum is different is that
ethereum allows developers to upload
their code to it and run it when code is
uploaded to the ethereum blockchain
three very important things happen the
code is able to receive and send money
just like a human would
no one even the creator of the code can
edit the code or delete it and anyone at
any point can run that code enter
tornado cache
tornado cache is a piece of code
uploaded to the ethereum blockchain that
allows users to have anonymous
transactions by creating a disconnection
between the person sending the money and
the person receiving the money the way
it works is brilliant and pretty
straightforward if you want to send 10
coins from a to b and you do it directly
everybody will know they will know how
much you send from who to who and when
to create a disconnect between the
sender and the receiver you can send
those 10 coins to tornado cash there
your coins will be put in a pool that
holds all the coins of all tornado cash
users effectively mixing them that's why
it's called a mixer
when you want to withdraw you can go
back to tornado cache and you can
receive the 10 coins that you deposited
on a brand new address effectively
creating the disconnect i know what
you're thinking this isn't private at
all if i deposit
333 coins in tornado cash and then some
anonymous user withdraws 333 coins they
will know it was me now this is why
tornado cash doesn't accept just any
amount you can only withdraw and deposit
0.1 or 1 or 10 or 100 it another
question you might have is how does
tornado cash know if the person that is
withdrawing the coins made a deposit
before without revealing their identity
when you send and deposit your coins in
tornado cash you will send them along
with a hash like a signature that only
you can create tornado cash will save
your deposit along with your signature
when it's time to withdraw you don't
send the signature because if you did it
will be very easy to know your identity
instead you will send something called a
zero knowledge proof which basically
means that you will prove to tornado
cash that you hold a signature that was
sent before but you don't need to reveal
what signature it is zero knowledge
proofs allows you to prove that you know
something without revealing what
something is they are an amazing
cryptographic invention and they're
actually very hard to explain in a few
seconds so if you want me i could make a
video about it because it's a
mind-blowing almost magical thing the
8th of august of 2022 tornado cache was
sanctioned by the u.s government saying
that it has been used to launder more
than seven billion dollars of
cryptocurrency tornado cash was added to
the specially designated nationals and
blocked persons lists of the office of
foreign assets control aka ofac what
that basically means is that it is
illegal for any u.s citizen resident or
company to do business with any entity
on that list which by the way includes
actors such as cuba iran and north korea
and it now contains the address of the
tornado cash code and all its related
wallets which means that any u.s person
or entity that interacts with tornado
caches code might be breaking the law it
might be subject to a fine and potential
jail time now after this happened many
u.s companies started to freak out so
the source code of tornado cache was
deleted from github github also banned
the personal accounts of tornado cash's
developers the company behind the usdc a
stablecoin blacklisted the coins stored
in the tornado cash code and a man being
a suspect of being a tornado cash
developer was arrested in the
netherlands now it's very worrying that
they are going after the tool and the
developers of that tool instead of going
after the bad actors that use the tool
it is true that north korean hackers and
other bad actors actually use tornado
cash to launder their stolen funds that
is a fact but north korean hackers are
also potentially using privacy services
like vpns should we go after vpn
providers and developers money
laundering isn't the only reason why
people use tornado cash it's just a
privacy solution vitalik buttering the
creator of ethereum said that he has
used tornado cash before as a privacy
tool to donate to ukrainian refugees and
protect their identity the 7 billion
dollar figure that is mentioned on the
sanction might not actually be a hundred
percent accurate seven billion is the
amount of money that has passed through
tornado cash in its lifetime on this
chart you can see where the money that
interacts with tornado comes from as you
can see some of it comes from stolen
phones and suction actors but most of it
comes from defy users and centralized
exchanges nevertheless it looks like
these sanctions will get challenged in
court since the tornado cash contract
isn't a person or a company it's just
code and code seems to be protected
under free speech now keep in mind that
according to ofac quotes the ultimate
goal of sanctions is not to punish but
to bring about a positive change in
behavior every year ofac removes
hundreds of individuals and entities
from the sdn list if that's the case if
they don't want to punish but instead
they want to change to a positive
behavior it makes no sense to add
tornado cash's code to that list that
code is immutable it doesn't have agency
it cannot change behavior it's just code
and also from a technical point of view
enforcing these sanctions might not be
feasible after the sanctions were
announced people that had money in
tornado cash spent more than 50 000
dollars withdrawing 0.18 to high profile
ethereum addresses like for example the
ceo of coinbase or the nft artist people
jimmy fallon dave chappelle snoop dogg
and the basketball player shaquille
o'neal those people are all u.s citizens
and because of how blockchain works you
cannot reject a transaction so this
means that on paper those people have
interacted with the tornado caches
contract which means they're breaking
the law for example what happens if an
ethereum us validator processes a
transaction from somebody in peru that
is interacting with tornado cash is the
validator breaking the law for
facilitating money laundering if that
was true then maybe u.s validators will
have to run their own version of
ethereum that excludes and checks for
sanctioned addresses and code if they
did that then the rest of the world will
exclude that chain and we will end up
with ethereum and ethereum usa to
conclude tornado cache is still
operating it's still running it can't be
taken down showing the power and the
censorship resistance of blockchain and
the ethereum network north korean
hackers can still use tornado cash but
u.s citizens lost access to a tool that
gives them privacy now to be clear i
think that we should go after hackers
and people that steal money but i don't
think we should go after tools and
developers of those tools that will hurt
innovation what these sanctions exposed
is how much the crypto community is
relying on the u.s service providers
that are subject to u.s sanctions and
law with the move to proof-of-stake u.s
exchanges that have a lot of heat will
become very powerful validators which
means that if the u.s law requires them
they might have to censor transactions
on the blocks they provide which might
create a sensor version of the ethereum
network maybe creating a hard fork or
slashing the user's funds who knows
thank you for watching this video let me
know in the comments what would you do
would you ban a tool because it's used
by bad people but also by good people
what do you think let me know in the
comments i'm very curious about what you
have to say thank you as always for
watching and don't forget if you want to
learn to code and you want to do it for
absolutely free then please click the
link below and i will see you there stay
free stay healthy eat genji
see you on the next one
[Music]
tomato constructor
you